In the end, Rosemyne accepted four
children into the monastery in Hasse.
However,
the mayor of Hasse, who was planning
to sell those children to the nobility,
did not look kindly upon Rosemyne.
We received quite a cold
reception in Hasse...
You knew about this, didn't you, Benno?
Yes. This is precisely the kind of
treatment one would expect from Hasse.
Ascendance of a Bookworm:
Adopted Daughter of an Archduke
Episode 8
Ferdinand's Task
The mayor of Hasse holds considerable
influence over the entire region.
The territory of Ehrenfest is
divided into two types of land:
regions managed by the land-owning
nobles known as Giebes,
and domains directly governed by the Aub.
Hasse is one of the directly governed
domains and has been entrusted
with the administration of the
surrounding farming villages, as well.
A great number of people gather
at the winter mansion in Hasse
to make it through the winter.
The town mayor is the one who
controls that winter mansion.
I find it hard to believe he would
grow so arrogant based on that alone.
What I wish to know is what
kind of noble backer he has.
Judging by his demeanor toward
us, a party involved with
a major industry of Ehrenfest,
when we visited for our inspection...
I believe he has connections with
a noble of a very high rank.
Hmm. I am certain that the former
high bishop was one of his backers.
Huh?
The previous high bishop
did not have a highbeast.
His movements would have been restricted
to areas accessible by carriage.
He probably flaunted his status as
the archduke's uncle
to do whatever he pleased.
Above all, their methods
are strikingly similar.
How can he remain so arrogant after
the high bishop has been apprehended?
Perhaps he's unaware the
high bishop was imprisoned?
His understanding of your
status is still likely...
Huh? That's...
Isn't that the blue priest that came
to the Spring Prayer last year?
Then, he isn't even aware that I've
been adopted by the archduke?
Of course not.
Benno, what kind of rumors
have been circulating
in the lower city regarding
the former high bishop?
There aren't any.
There have been rumors that
the new high bishop is a saint
that can bestow real blessings,
but everyone just assumed the
former high bishop retired
and haven't given it much thought.
That's why I said that Project
Saint was taking things too far...
Even after his death, he
continues to cause trouble.
He's mulling over something again.
High Priest, I just felt
something strange...
It seems someone is attempting to force
their way into the monastery in Hasse.
I can feel a faint disturbance
of the defensive walls.
Huh?!
Come, Rosemyne.
Spiegeln.
It's the monastery in Hasse!
Oh, there are people.
In all likelihood, they've
come to reclaim the children.
Huh?!
We know you're in there!
Come out!
What the heck are you doing?
Leave this to me!
No!
What the hell is this?
It seems the defensive magic
is working without any issues.
Defensive magic?
Yes.
Didn't you infuse mana into the
feystones of the monastery?
Oh, back then...
The defensive magic used
is similar to the kind you used
when you were being attacked.
The shield of wind!
It prevents anyone bearing ill will
toward those inside from entering.
Well, that's a relief.
Let's take this chance to
check on Nora and the others.
Not right now.
If we aren't careful, the mayor
will be silenced like Wolf was.
People involved with me are
killed without my knowledge...
I would hate that.
Yes.
It seems this man holds a great
deal of evidence in his hands,
so I would like to capture him alive.
Do not visit Hasse until the
next day of inspection.
Yes...
A few days later...
A letter addressed to the
former high bishop arrived.
"One of your subordinates is behaving
with the utmost arrogance."
"Please do something about the monastery."
Like the high priest said...
They don't know that the
former high bishop is dead?
"Even Nora, who was contracted
to be sold to the nobility,
has been snatched away from us."
This is...
It seems he doesn't know the first
thing about writing letters.
Come to think of it, Mr. Benno said...
Hasse has no facilities for
nobles to dine or lodge in.
Since it's located close
to the city of Ehrenfest,
everyone simply passes through it.
Because of that, the villagers
have no interaction with nobles
except for religious ceremonies
and tax collection.
No wonder the mayor has
gotten so arrogant.
Reply that the previous high
bishop has passed away.
I wish to confirm what he truly desires,
a high bishop that brings
blessings to Hasse
or a noble that will line his pockets?
But doesn't this serve as
evidence of his misconduct?
Is it truly all right
to turn a blind eye?
We have no choice but
to let him be for now.
It would be easy to remove him, but what
truly matters is what comes after.
But... Isn't it better to purge such
petty wrongdoers as soon as possible?
Rosemyne, what wrongdoing has he done?
Huh?
Well... He sells children.
And he's also trying to offer
money and valuables in
exchange for special favors...
And what's wrong with that?
Huh?
The mayor takes care of
the orphaned children.
In exchange, he holds the rights
of ownership over them.
It is within the mayor's
right to sell them or not.
The same applies here in the
cathedral of Ehrenfest.
That's right. That's the common
sense of this world...
Furthermore, while you call it a bribe,
you are asking a noble to
make exceptions for you.
Isn't it natural that you'd want
to make a good impression?
Didn't Benno do the very same
thing at our first meeting?
Back then, I was thinking of it as
just a token of appreciation...
But when you put it that way,
I can't really explain how Benno
is different from the mayor.
Huh?
Then, the mayor hasn't
done anything wrong?
He has.
His crime lies in disobeying
the orders of a noble like me
and raising an objection to our decision.
So, selling children and offering
bribes aren't considered crimes...
That's right.
If the proceeds from selling the children,
even through some illicit means,
is used to bring prosperity to the town,
the people of Hasse will
stand by their mayor.
Huh?
Benno mentioned that even the
surrounding farming villages
gather at the winter mansion in Hasse.
If the townsfolk are told
that he was planning
to use the money gained
from selling the children to nobles
to provide for the large number
of people through the winter,
we, who selfishly snatched
the children from them,
would become the targets
of the townsfolk's hatred.
I know very well how vital winter
preparations are for commoners.
When comparing the many citizens who pay
their taxes to a handful of children,
it's obvious that priority should be
taken to protect the townspeople.
In other words, to the people
of Hasse, we're the villains?
As things currently stand, yes.
I was too naive!
I was just thinking
that I could gain a workforce and those
children could gain a stable life.
That's why building a monastery seemed
like such a convenient solution, but...
This is what he meant
when he said not to think
that things would
conveniently go my way.
Since this project was approved
as a territory-wide initiative,
I didn't even think about
whether or not it would cause
the people of Hasse any problems.
The archduke gave you
permission to do this because
he determined we would be able to collect
taxes from the new laborers you create.
This isn't a simple act of compassion.
Currently, you live off of the
taxes paid by the citizens.
The children and the taxpayers.
Can you not tell which of the
two must be prioritized?
I understand now...
I will arrange compensation for
the mayor for the children.
That will resolve this matter, won't it?
What are you saying?
That man defied me, a noble.
He needs to be disposed of.
What? But this is all my fault!
I never imagined our conceptions of
wrongdoing would be so different.
This is perfect.
That little bug will serve as an
excellent teaching tool for you.
Create a faction opposing the mayor,
nurture it, and isolate him.
Come again?
I am telling you to prepare a successor
that will ensure the town of Hasse
will continue functioning smoothly
once we remove the mayor.
If you cultivate a convenient pawn
that aligns with our interests
before we eliminate him, things
will fall neatly into place.
Give it a try.
You want me to entrap someone?
Didn't I tell you?
You must be the one to force
things to go your way.
I grew up being taught that something
like that was a bad thing to do...
Morality
No... I'm scared.
I don't want to do something like that!
Pull yourself together.
If you don't act, the children cannot
venture out into the forest.
The workshop will grind to a halt.
They would become nuisances that only eat
the divine blessings provided for them.
Surely, you didn't plan
to selfishly abduct them,
lock them away, and put
them into an environment
where they would be shunned by others?
But... But...
I don't know how to plot against others.
It's your first time, after all.
I will teach you how.
Ascendance of a
Bookworm:
Adopted Daughter of an Archduke
Ascendance of a
Bookworm:
Adopted Daughter of an Archduke
"Give it a try."
"I will teach you how."
I returned to the castle
for the time being
to have my measurements
taken for my winter attire.
What's wrong? You look pale.
I couldn't sleep thinking about
the task you gave me for Hasse.
Something as trivial as that?
You are far too weak.
It may seem trivial to the high priest,
but it's an impossible challenge to me...
Little princess, you look rather
pale. Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
Brother Wilfried.
Rosemyne, you're back home.
Young Master, where are your attendants?
Oh, well...
M-More importantly, where
are you guys going?
Are you going to see Father again?
Huh?
That's what I thought...
Why does Rosemyne get to see
Father so much?! It's unfair!
Please stop, Lord Wilfried!
I hate you! Stupid!
You're the stupid one, Brother Wilfried!
You're always running from your studies
and causing everyone around you trouble!
I want to run away, too!
But if I do...
If you were more dependable,
I wouldn't have received such an
unreasonable task from Lord Ferdinand!
Y-You're being too cheeky, Rosemyne!
Please control yourself, Lady Rosemyne!
After that, due to the opening
of the Italian restaurant,
I went to my adoptive father to
have him return Hugo, the chef.
A few days later...
It must have been scary.
Is everyone all right?
Can... May I speak?
Her speech has improved.
Her complexion, too...
Those people weren't able to do anything.
I was surprised, but I also
felt a sense of relief!
Me, too!
I'm glad to know that my sister
definitely can't be taken away!
We get to eat proper meals
all the time, too...
I heard from everyone that you were
the one who thought of all of this.
Even though you're smaller than
me, you're pretty awesome!
I'm glad we decided to come here.
I'm happy just to see
Marthe smiling again.
Thank you, Lady Rosemyne.
The way I did things may have been wrong,
but it wasn't wrong to
accept these children...
I want to find a way for
both the town of Hasse
and these children to
have a good outcome.
But how can I do that?
What happened? You look terrible.
Lutz, the task the high priest gave me...
That's pretty lenient of him.
Lenient?! How so?!
I haven't been able to
sleep for days now!
I'm not talking about you.
I'm talking about Hasse.
It wouldn't have been strange
for the entire town of Hasse
to be burned to the ground the moment
they attacked the monastery.
Burn the entire town of
Hasse to the ground?
The monastery is a white building
that the archduke established at the
request of his adopted daughter.
Launching an attack against it is the
same as attacking the archduke's family.
What?! Really?!
Don't tell me you didn't realize that?
I didn't...
You already know what happens
to someone who attacks a member
of the archduke's family, right?
Count Bindewald was imprisoned
for attacking me,
the archduke's adopted daughter.
Since even nobles are punished, there's
no way commoners wouldn't be.
Then...
If I wasn't given this task, Hasse...
The entire town would
have been long gone.
Hasse will be finished the moment the
attack becomes public knowledge.
Even merchants do things like creating
opposing factions to stir the pot.
It's something you'll eventually have to
learn as the archduke's daughter anyway.
Like the high priest said, this is
an excellent teaching tool for you.
But...
I don't want to do something
like scheme and entrap someone.
Then, just change your way of thinking.
Huh?
You're not entrapping the mayor.
You're saving the people of Hasse who
are getting dragged into this mess
because of the mayor. Right?
I'm saving the people of Hasse...
Yeah, you're saving them.
After all, the high bishop of Ehrenfest
is a saint who can bestow real
divine blessings to others.
If I think of it that way,
I think I can do it...
Your complexion has improved a lot.
I was able to gain advice
from Lutz and the others.
And what of the task I gave you?
Yes.
We will create rumors.
Hm, what kind of rumors?
The monastery in Hasse was attacked
and now the entire town is in danger.
The compassionate high bishop fears
that even though the attackers were
people related to the town mayor,
the innocent townsfolk that have nothing
to do with it will be punished as well.
At the same time, we will
circulate another rumor.
Who is going to be held
accountable for the attack?
Steer clear of Hasse if you want to
avoid getting dragged into this mess.
This sense of unease, along with
their fear of the nobility,
should morph into resentment
against the mayor's faction,
allowing us to isolate him completely.
I'm a little surprised that
Mr. Mark and the high priest
are actually the same type of people.
The speed that rumors spread
by merchants is really crazy!
In that case, we have no choice
but to go through with it.
However, if we spread these rumors, the
incident in Hasse will become public knowledge.
A fitting plan for someone like you,
who has deep ties with the lower city.
How interesting.
Do as you planned.
Yes!
Even so, I can't believe you didn't even
realize the meaning of attacking the monastery.
Looks like he won't turn a
blind eye to that part...
Translation   Angela Tamae Liu
Timing   Edgar Cruz
Editing   Tara Campbell
QC   Alicia Ashby
FQC   Michelle Tymon
Next Episode
Wilfried's Day as High Bishop
Why did you fail to grasp the significance
of the attack on the monastery?
Our common sense is too different.
Don't you understand that better than
anyone, since you peered into my memories?
I recall you seemed to have
a rather comfortable life...
Weren't you the daughter of
an upper-class noble family?
There aren't any nobles in that world.
We don't even have a class system.
It seems I will have to reconsider your
education plan from the very foundations.
Illustration: Kikuta Yui